punit tiwari



CONTACT

- **⋈**punitjee@gmail.com
- n +91 9720332057
- C-84, Pocket-7 Sector 82, 201305 Noida, India

ABOUT ME

Proactive, Analytical and Self-directed Manager (Process Automation) with almost Ten (10) years of rich experience in IT industry with extensive expertise in RPA (UiPath), Process Automation & Testing. Currently leading Production Support in RPA for GE Healthcare.

EXPERIENCE

Manager RPA

Genpact - Since April 2019



- ▶ Identifying scope for Change/Improvement in existing Production BOTs, able to save additional 0.5 to 1.0 FTE in several BOTs.
- ▶ As a SME, Working closely with Business Teams to help them realize the ROI after Automation is delivered, conceptualizing new opportunities for Automation Scope, Designing End To End Solution and leading team to develop the complete solution.
- ▶ Leading Team to Develop Reusable Component Library to ease out the automation & Reduce Development Time.
- ► Leading Production Support Team for Production bots involving Web, Desktop, Excel and Outlook Applications. 0% SLA Violation till date.

Lead: Automation

Peak Business Insides Ltd - April 2018 to March 2019



- ▶ Worked closely with Process SME's to translate process into Process Definition Document (PDD) & Solution Design Document (SDD).
- ▶ Designed End to End Automation Suite to support Unit Testing to reduce Development time.
- Facilitated End To End Integration and UAT
- ▶ Did almost all kind of automation for example: Excel Automation, Web Automation, Email Automation, PDF Automation, Image/OCR Automation and etc.
- ▶ Developed Framework to test Web Application & movement of Data from AWS using Selenium.

Sr. Analyst | Test Delivery Lead



Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd - June 2015 to February 2018

- ► Conceptualized and designed End To End Automated process on Oracle Web Application Process (OTM), saved 1 FTE.
- ► Conceptualized and designed Integrated automation suite for Order Processing System and report generation.
- Conceptualized and designed Web Automation Suite to help Functional Testing, saved 40 man hours in Regression Testing.
- ▶ Involved in requirements gathering, solution designing, coding, testing, debugging, documentation and implementation.
- ▶ Finding automation opportunities in existing process and implementing them.
- Developing and maintaining Test Scripts, analyzing bugs and interacting with development team members in fixing the defects.
- ▶ Testing of new releases, Automating scripts using Selenium and running on slave machine via Jenkins, Defect Logging.
- ▶ Worked on various tools like Eclipse, Selenium, Work-soft, HP ALM, JIRA, Jenkins.
- ▶ Design and execution of Test Strategies, Traceability Matrix, Test Plans, Capacity Estimation, Test Scenarios, Test cases, Test reports, Test results and documentation for complex applications in large projects and Programs.
- ▶ Increased automation coverage from 0% to 60% using selenium automation which saved a lot of time and money for client.

UAT - Lead

ColdEX Logistics India Pvt Ltd - January 2013 to May 2015



- ► Collaborated with Developers and Subject Matter Experts and worked as a single POC through which requirements flows.
- ► Interpreted Business Requirements and translated them in to application and operational requirements
- ► Examined all aspects of WMS software from business operations prospective to find the GAPs, worked closely with development team to eliminate those GAPs
- ▶ Lead a team of 2 resources & successfully conducted User Acceptance Testing. Prepared a detailed KT manual on various business modules and trained new resources on them.

Sr Executive Quality & Testing



iProf India Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd -June 2009 to December 2012

- Prepared test plan and designing & reviewing the test cases based on functional specifications. Setting-up test environment, and functional test execution records.
- ▶ Created Company's first comprehensive database of documented test defects and procedures to enable accurate replication and ensure compliance with standards. Accelerated average QA testing turn-around time by 25% or more.
- ▶ Documented software defects using bug tracking system and reported defects involving program functionality, output, online screen and content to software developers

SKILLS

RPA Tools

▶ UiPath
★★★☆☆

Automation Tools

 ▶ Selenium WebDriver
 ★★☆☆
 ▶ Worksoft-Certify

 ▶ JMeter
 ★☆☆☆
 ▶ Jenkins

 ▶ Maven
 ★★☆☆

Software Packages

Web Technologies

 ▶ XML
 ★★☆☆☆ ▶ SQL

 ▶ EDI
 ★★☆☆ ▶ Java

 ▶ VB Scripting
 ★☆☆☆ ▶ Python

Functional

▶ SDLC / STLC

▶ Agile (Scrum) / DevOps ★★★☆ ♪ BDD / BDT

★★★☆ → SCM (WMS/TMS)

► Gap Analysis / UAT

 $\star\star\star\star$

Certifications

- ▶ ISTOB (CTFL-8079961)
- ▶ UiPath Orchestrator 2016.2
- Worksoft Certify Fundamentals
- ▶ IBM-Big Data Foundations Level 1 (2016)
- ▶ UiPAth Foundation Training
- ▶ UiPath Advanced Developer 2019.4.2
- Microsoft (98-369) MTA Cloud Fundamentals (13476828)

EDUCATION

MTech (Engineering Physics)

USBAS IP University New Delhi 2006 to 2008

MSc (Electronics)

CCSU Meerut 2003 to 2005